I'm sure we all remember a time when we fell in love.
我相信我们都记得自己坠入爱河的那一刻。
For some it was a gradual realisation that the person you knew was actually amazing.
对有些人来说，是逐渐意识到自己认识的那个人其实非常出色。
For others, it was love at first sight - an instant lightning-bolt moment that you knew you'd met your perfect match.
而对另一些人来说，则是一见钟情——一个瞬间的闪电般的时刻，让你知道自己遇到了完美的另一半。
What is it that makes someone instantly love someone?
是什么让人会立刻爱上另一个人呢？
Physical attraction is an obvious answer but there are other reasons that can create affection for someone; compatibility, personality and a good sense of humour to name just a few.
外表上的吸引是一个显而易见的答案，但还有其他一些能让人产生爱慕之情的原因，比如性格相投、个性以及幽默感等等。
But according to one expert, there is a more scientific explanation.
但据一位专家说，还有更科学的解释。
Dr Anna Machin, an Evolutionary Anthropologist at the University of Oxford says men look for signs of fertility and good health in a partner "and the major indicator of that in women is the waist-hip ratio... the absolute ideal."
牛津大学的进化人类学家安娜·马钦博士说，男性会在伴侣身上寻找生育能力和健康的迹象，“女性该迹象的主要的指标是腰臀比……绝对的理想状态”。
This is believed to be 0.7 which is "really your classic hourglass figure."
据信这个比例是0.7，也就是“真正经典的沙漏型身材”。
And what do women look for in men?
那么女性会在男性身上寻找什么呢？
Well other experts have discovered they look for men who are taller, with broad shoulders and a relatively narrow waist - so a 'V' shaped torso.
其他专家发现，她们会寻找更高、肩膀宽阔且腰部相对较窄的男性，也就是“V”字形的躯干。
If you're worried your figure isn't the perfect shape, there could be other factors that will cause someone to fall head over heels in love with you - people also use their sense of smell to sniff out their ideal mate.
如果你担心自己的身材不够完美，还有其他一些因素可能会让别人深深地爱上你，人们还会用嗅觉来寻觅自己理想的伴侣。
Apparently, we can detect whether people are genetically different to us by the way they smell.
显然，我们可以通过一个人的气味来判断他们在基因上是否与我们不同。
Even if a potential partner's smell is a passion-killer, their facial expressions might make you infatuated with them.
即使潜在伴侣的气味是个激情杀手，他们的面部表情也可能会让你迷恋上他们。
According to Professor David Perrett, at the School of Psychology and Neuroscience at St Andrews University, "we can change our faces by interacting with others and doing so in a pleasant manner, and that will aid our attractiveness and make others interested in us."
圣安德鲁斯大学心理学与神经科学学院的大卫·佩雷特教授说：“我们可以通过以愉快的方式与他人互动来改变自己的面部表情，这将有助于提升我们的吸引力，让别人对我们感兴趣。”
So it's good to know there are many reasons why we might be smitten with someone but there is a problem; will the feeling be mutual and if it is, how long will it last?
所以很高兴知道我们可能会因为很多原因而爱上某个人，但这里有个问题：这种感觉会是相互的吗？如果是，又能持续多久呢？
Nothing is guaranteed and, we know from Shakespeare, the course of true love never ran smoothly!
没有什么是可以保证的，而且正如我们从莎士比亚的作品中了解到的，真爱的道路从来都不是一帆风顺的！